Marcus Loo Vergara

Oslo, Norway

☎ NO +47 411 78 583 • @ contact@marcusv.io • ♦ bitsauce.github.io

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

M.Sc. in Computer Science. Graduated from the Norwegian University of Science and Technology June 2019. Specialized in computer graphics and real-time computational systems, with an additional interest in deep learning. Self-motivated, quick learner, and enjoy collaborating with others.

• C. C++ & Rust

• Vulkan, DX11 & OpenGL

GPGPU

Pvthon

• API Design

Deep Learning

• Windows & Linux

• Frontend, Qt, UI

• Network Programming

EDUCATION

Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway

Master of Science in Computer Science

• Specializing in computer graphics, computer vision, and deep learning

Aug 2013 - Jun 2019

University of California, San Diego, San Diego, USA

Additional Studies, Computer Science

• Studying at UC San Diego as part of my degree

Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer at myVR/Hexagon, Oslo, Norway Software Developer

Aug 2024 - Present

Nov 2022 - Aug 2024

Full-time R&D position focusing on rendering of parametrically defined geometry in addition to optimizing API-level rendering code for mobile, desktop and web platforms

- Extending the internal multiplatform rendering API with modern features
 - Compute shaders, storage buffers, uniform buffers, etc.
 - Must support DirectX11, DirectX12, Vulkan, OpenGL, WebGL, WebGPU, Metal
- Optimized rendering of parametric geometry showing improvements up to 30% on some devices
- Adding functionality to convert and visualize CAD files

Drone Software Engineer at Nordic Unmanned, Oslo, Norway

Feb 2021 - Nov 2022

Full-time position developing custom software solutions for maintenance and delivery drones

- Writing drivers to read IMU data from the on-board sensors
- Improving and extending in-house simulator capabilities
- Implementing video streaming, focusing on stability over low-bandwidth links
- Integrating and testing third-party hardware and microcontrollers

Junior Graphics Programmer at Funcom, Oslo, Norway

Oct 2019 - Feb 2021

Full-time position as an Unreal Engine rendering programmer working on Dune: Awakening

- Researching modern rendering techniques and extending Unreal Engine's rendering capabilities
- Optimizing development workflows for artists and other users
- Fulfilling internal support and debugging of rendering issues

Graphics Software Engineering Intern at Sony Interactive Ent., San Mateo, USA Jul 2018 - Sep 2018 Internship at SIEA's Global Developer Technology Group

- Implemented a physically-based shading model running on the PlayStation 4
- Investigated possibilities for implementing tools to extract and analyze GPU performance data

Software Developer at Grabster, Trondheim, Norway

Jul 2017 – Aug 2017

Summer job assisting a start-up with app development

Grabster was a food-selling marketplace app for iOS and Android

• Implemented screen navigation and backend functionality for the Android app (React Native)

Teaching Assistant at the Norwegian University of Science and Technology On-campus part-time job assisting students

Aug 2015 - May 2019

- Support and advising in solving theoretical and practical questions
- Assigned subjects:
 - Jan 2019 May 2019: Computer vision and deep learning
 - Jan 2016 May 2017: Procedural and object-oriented programming (C++)
 - Aug 2015 Dec 2015: Computers and digital design (Assembly programming)

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Game Engine Programming, Side-project

2011 - Present

Written a game engine from scratch and making a GPGPU heavy sandbox physics game using it

- Supported rendering APIs: Vulkan and DirectX11 (previously OpenGL 4.2)
- Threaded rendering and performance metrics
- Focused on programmer-centric workflows to simplify development
- See Twitter or Bluesky for more:
 - https://x.com/bitsaucedev
 - https://bsky.app/profile/bitsauce.bsky.social

Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Vehicles, Thesis

Sep 2018 - Jun 2019

Research in the field of deep reinforcement learning, implementing methods to teach a simulated car to drive inside the open-source driving simulator, *CARLA*

- Implemented a custom version of the *Proximal Policy Optimization* reinforcement learning method with *Python* and *TensorFlow*
- Created an *OpenAI gym*-like environment that works with CARLA to make RL research in CARLA easier
- Substantially reduced training time through experimentation with reward functions, environment designs, and improvements to the PPO algorithm by scaling the output mean to respective limits
- Video of results: https://voutu.be/iF502iJKTIY

MISCELLANEOUS

Seismic Map Illustration for European Standard, Commissioned Work

Apr 2021

Used official seismic data from EFEHR along with geographical boundaries of municipalities in Norway to programmatically create a seismic map, printed in the official standard: *NS-EN* 1998-1:2004+A1:2013+NA:2021.

Teaching Assistant Training, Norwegian University of Science and Technology May 2019 – May 2019 Certificate awarded for attending a pedagogical training course for teaching assistants

Abakus GameDev, Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Co-founder and leader of student organization *Abakus GameDev* – a student organization for people who enjoy making games, discussing their development, design, and the industry in general

- Responsible for creating a socket-based framework that was used for AI competitions
- Participates in meetings, discussing workshop ideas and advertising
- Held a presentation on deep reinforcement learning for games